# Carlos A. Ramos K.

### **Senior Software Developer**

I am a computer scientist with experience in development and agile practices. I have been working with Ruby on Rails for about 10+ years and is my framework of choice. Fell in love with the Ruby way of doing things and its syntax but recently open-minded with functional programming and Elixir. I am obsessed to write code elegant and tested, also I am a big fan of DDD as my choice when needed architect decisions.

I'm looking for projects with challenging problems like real-time geo-localization, data processing/ingestion, streaming using event sourcing, refactoring and performance of legacy code.

### **SKILLS**

| Platforms    |         |            |          |          |               |
|--------------|---------|------------|----------|----------|---------------|
| Linux        | MacOS   |            |          |          |               |
| Technologies |         |            |          |          |               |
| Ruby         | Elixir  | NodeJS     | Ember.js | Angular  | Ruby on Rails |
| Phoenix      | GraphQL | TDD        | DDD      |          |               |
| Databases    |         |            |          |          |               |
| PostgresQL   | Mysql   |            |          |          |               |
| Others       |         |            |          |          |               |
| RabbitMQ     | Rspec   | jQuery     | CSS      | JSON:API | PostGIS       |
| Gen-Server   | ОТР     | Typescript |          |          |               |
| Soft Skills  |         |            |          |          |               |

Management, Mentoring, Continuous learning.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Zenlabs CTO, Senior developer, Freelancer La Paz, Bolivia (Sept 2011 - Current)

Lead a team of developers working on small and medium startups.

During this time I took part in the following projects:

**Printfor.me** Printing services on the cloud, I develop integration with Dropbox, Google Docs, add the functionality of real-time, export to PDF, accounting and creation of tests.

**MYeCFO** social network for investments, I lead a team working on creating a social network, create and maintain the test suite.

**Framinco** Processing and upload images with geolocalization, upgrade to the latest versions of ruby, rails, design/implementation of API's for Mobile clients, Performance and deploy on heroku.

**Novelo** Big facebook app for Ecommerce, Test with Rspec, Facebook API, Jquery, Heroku.

**Nuki** Point of Sale app, Team Lead, design/implementation of API's, a single page app, Backbone, Offline, Transactional, Test with Rspec, Jasmine.

**Doolebrate** Project management/ Time tracker, Upgrade versions of Ruby and Rails, Continuous Integration with CircleCI, Heroku integration and enhance of the test suite.

Technologies: Ruby 1.8, ruby 2.x, Rspec, Capybara, Pusher.io, Ruby on Rails, Backbone.js

# Expedition.ws Full Stack Developer

Remote, La Paz, Bolivia (Dec 2016 - Dec 2018)

Built and coding with the founder a social network about traveling, focused on interactions as chat-rooms, geolocalization, videos, places suggestions.

Full-stack developer, developed an API's using Elixir, web sockets, social network features, geolocalization, media processing with phoenix/OTP through JSON:API endpoints, integration to Ember.js, Progressive web app (PWA) webworker's.

Technologies: Elixir, Ember.js, Json:API, Websockets, TDD.

# Mojix Senior Developer

La Paz, Bolivia (May 2015 Feb 2016)

IoT Company,

During this time I took part in the following projects:

- Pinc Solutions (May 2015 Feb 2016).
  - Worked in a Big Warehouse management System, for income/outcome of assets and orchestration using micro-services.
  - Refactoring and improving legacy code.
  - Transition to use Event Sourcing trough persisted Websockets.
  - Upgrade versions of ruby, rails.
  - Design and implement API's as Micro-services.

- Add file uploads to Amazon S3 storage.
- Improve the Rspec test suite and performance.

Technologies: Ruby, Rails, PostgresQL, Redis, Rspec.

TeraCode Software Developer Buenos Aires, Argentina (Sep 2009 - May 2010)

A big software factory, that makes solutions using the latest technology.

#### **Blueleaf**

As I part of outsourcing team I developed features of the first version of financial startup, Did integrations with third parties services using JSON, XML-RPC, SOAP, integration to Yodlee, Rspec tests using TDD in a highly growing up startup

Technologies: Ruby, Rails, haml, Rspec.

Freelancing
Software Developer

La Paz, Bolivia (2006-2009)

Work with Ruby on Rails to develop CasasMap.com a Real state startup idea and also develop a lot of websites with RoR.

Development of an online class booking system, the system generates student payment receipts, reports of classes and accounting reports.

# **EDUCATION**

2012 - 2007

Computer Science Engineer

Universidad Mayor de San Andres

# **LANGUAGES**

Spanish: Native English:

Upper-Intermediate

**HOBBIES** 

photography draw